Professors

cancel

at

Log InSign Up

Advertisement

Privacy Policy
==============

Advertisement

**RATEMYPROFESSORS.COM PRIVACY POLICY**

PRIVACY POLICY AND CALIFORNIA RESIDENTS: NOTICE OF PRIVACY RIGHTS

This is the privacy policy ("Privacy Policy") describing our privacy practices for the RateMyProfessors.com website, applications and other interactive services ("Site"). The Site is owned, operated and/or provided by Rate My Professors, LLC ("Rate My Professors," "we," "us," or "our"). This Privacy Policy is intended to explain our privacy practices and covers the following areas:

1. [When This Privacy Policy Applies.](#sectionp1)
2. [U.S. Governing Law.](#sectionp2)
3. [What Information Is Collected.](#sectionp3)
4. [How Is Collected Information Used.](#sectionp4)
5. [Your Choices.](#sectionp5)
6. [\[reserved\]](#sectionp6)
7. [Sharing and Disclosure of Information.](#sectionp7)
8. [Reviewing, Updating or Deleting Certain Information.](#sectionp8)
9. [Protection of Information.](#sectionp9)
10. [California Residents: Notice of Privacy Rights.](#sectionp10)
11. [Additional State Privacy Laws.](#sectionp11)
12. [Changes to this Privacy Policy and Notice.](#sectionp12)
13. [Miscellaneous.](#sectionp13)

**1\. When This Privacy Policy Applies.** This Privacy Policy applies:

* Regardless of whether you are accessing the Site via a personal computer, a mobile device or any other technology or devices now known or hereafter developed or discovered (each, a "Device");
* Whether you are accessing the Site as a registered user (if offered by the Site) or other user of the Site;
* To all Information (as that term is defined below) collected by the Site (as defined above)
* To our use of combined information if we combine Information (as that term is defined below) collected by the Site with other information we collect from other sources, such as information received from Rate My Professors (for example, information collected at a physical location), marketing companies or Advertisers; and
* Will remain in full force and effect even if your use of or participation in the Site or any particular service, feature, function or promotional activity offered through the Site terminates, expires, ceases, is suspended or deactivated for any reason.

This Privacy Policy does not, unless specifically stated, apply to any Information (as that term is defined below) collected by any other company or collected in any other manner or by any other website, application or other interactive service offered by Rate My Professors.

By participating in this Site or any features, activities or services offered through the Site, you consent to our privacy practices as described in this Privacy Policy.

Certain products or services offered by this Site may be subject to additional privacy practices, such as practices on how Information is collected, used, shared and/or disclosed by such products or services and/or how you may exercise choice with regard to such Information ("Additional Privacy Statements"). These Additional Privacy Statements, if any, shall be provided to you in conjunction with those products and services and are hereby incorporated in this Privacy Policy by reference. To the extent that there is a conflict between this Privacy Policy and the Additional Privacy Statement for the activity in which you choose to participate, the Additional Privacy Statement shall govern.

**2\. U.S. Governing Law.** The Site is designed and targeted to U.S. audiences and is governed by and operated in accordance with the laws of the U.S. We make no representation that this Site is operated in accordance with the laws or regulations of, or governed by, other nations. If you are located outside of the U.S., you use this Site at your own risk and initiative and you, not us, are responsible for compliance with any applicable local and national laws. Please be aware that any Personal Information and Other Information you provide to us or we obtain as a result of your use of this Site shall be collected in the U.S. and/or transferred to the U.S. and subject to U.S. law. By using this Site, participating in any Site activities and/or providing us with your Personal Information and Other Information, you (a) consent to the transfer and/or processing of any Information to and in the U.S., (b) acknowledge that U.S. law may provide a lower standard of protection for personal data than the laws of your location and (c) understand that we shall collect, transfer, store, process and/or deal with your Information in accordance with this Privacy Policy and U.S. law. Consequently, to the full extent permitted by law, you hereby waive any claims relating to the processing of your Personal Information or Other Information in accordance with this Privacy Policy that may arise under the laws and regulations that apply to you in or of any other country or jurisdiction.

**3\. What Information Is Collected.** The Site is designed and targeted to U.S. audiences and is governed by and operated in accordance with the laws of the U.S. We make no representation that this Site is operated in accordance with the laws or regulations of, or governed by, other nations. If you are located outside of the U.S., you use this Site at your own risk and initiative and you, not us, are responsible for compliance with any applicable local and national laws. Please be aware that any Personal Information and Other Information you provide to us or we obtain as a result of your use of this Site shall be collected in the U.S. and/or transferred to the U.S. and subject to U.S. law. By using this Site, participating in any Site activities and/or providing us with your Personal Information and Other Information, you (a) consent to the transfer and/or processing of any Information to and in the U.S., (b) acknowledge that U.S. law may provide a lower standard of protection for personal data than the laws of your location and (c) understand that we shall collect, transfer, store, process and/or deal with your Information in accordance with this Privacy Policy and U.S. law. Consequently, to the full extent permitted by law, you hereby waive any claims relating to the processing of your Personal Information or Other Information in accordance with this Privacy Policy that may arise under the laws and regulations that apply to you in or of any other country or jurisdiction.

**3.1 Information You Provide.**

**3.1.1 User Registration** To register as a member of the Site, you are required to select a user name and password (together, your "User ID") and may be required to also provide other Information, such as your email address and date of birth. Additional Information may be requested and/or required during the registration process. After you have registered for the Site, we may recognize you when you visit certain other Rate My Professors websites, applications or other interactive services across Devices to register for and login on such other websites, applications or other interactive services, but please note that other Rate My Professors websites, applications or other interactive services may set additional or different requirements for membership, such as minimum age. Also note that, for your online privacy and security, if other people have access to your Device, we recommend you log out of your account after visiting any of the websites, applications or other interactive services that are associated with your account.

**3.1.2 In Connection with Certain Features and Functions.** We may also provide you with access to certain features or functions that we may offer on the Site, such as the option to participate in commenting, shopping and member profile pages. To sign up for or participate in these features or functions, you may be required to provide us with certain Information about you in order for us to personalize and/or allow you to use such features and functions.

**3.1.3 In Connection with Promotions such as Contests and Sweepstakes.** There may be a separate registration process to enter Promotions (as defined in the Site's [Terms of Use Agreement](https://www.ratemyprofessors.com/terms-of-use)) such as contests and sweepstakes which may require the submission of all or some of the following: your first and last name, street address, city, state and zip code, email address, telephone number and date of birth. Additional Information may be requested depending on the specific Promotion. The Promotion's entry page and/or Rules shall provide the specific requirements. You may also have the opportunity to opt-in to receive special Promotions or offers from our third party advertisers, sponsors or promotional partners ("Advertisers") as a result of your use of the Site in connection with these Promotions.

**3.2 Information Collected Through Use of Cookies and Other Tracking Technologies.** The Site and/or third parties may use "cookies", "web beacons", Flash local shared objects and other similar tracking technologies (collectively, "Tracking Technologies") to collect information automatically as you browse the Site and the web. "Cookies" are typically html or browser-based text or other files (and often referred to as browser cookies) that help store information, user preferences and/or user activity. "Web beacons" (also known as image tags, gif, tracking pixels or web bugs) are small pieces of code used to collect data, such as counting page views, promotion views or advertising responses. Flash local shared objects ("LSOs") (sometimes known as Flash cookies and used if Adobe Flash is used) are text or other files that help store user preferences and/or activity.

These Tracking Technologies collect "click stream" data and additional information regarding your visits to the Site (such as your visits to the Site's webpages, type of browser use, type of operating system used, date and time of viewing, use of our features and purchasing history or preferences) or other websites, applications or interactive services. Through these Tracking Technologies, we may collect such information across multiple sessions on this Site and other websites, applications or other interactive services and may also collect or access your IP address (which is automatically assigned to any Device(s) and/or Device and Internet browser combination you use to access the Site) and/or set or access some other identifier unique to the Device(s), Device platform and/or Device-Internet browser combination you use to access the Site ("Identifier"). For example, we may set a unique alphanumeric Identifier unique to your home computer on Firefox, or access an Identifier provided by a mobile platform, such as the application or advertising Identifiers offered by Apple. We may combine any or all of the information we collect using Tracking Technologies and associate it and/or Identifiers with the Personal Information you provide to us and/or with other non-personally identifiable unique identifiers assigned by Rate My Professors or third parties.

**3.2.1 The Site's Use of Tracking Technologies to Collect Information.** By visiting the Site, whether as a registered user or otherwise, you acknowledge and understand that you are giving us your consent to track your activities and your use of the Site and other websites, applications or interactive services through these Tracking Technologies and that we may use Tracking Technologies in the emails we send to you. See Your Choices section below for more information on how you can withdraw your consent for certain purposes.

We use Tracking Technologies to enable us to collect and then use Information as described in Section 4.2 below. For example, we may use Tracking Technologies to prevent you from seeing the same advertisements too many times or seeing advertisements too frequently, to tailor your experience on the Site by delivering relevant personalized advertising, email marketing and other content and to record if you have opted out of receiving personalized advertising from us.

**3.2.2 Third Parties' Use of Tracking Technologies to Collect Information.** This Site may additionally use a variety of third party advertising networks, data exchanges, data management platforms, supply side platforms, ad exchanges, traffic or audience measurement service providers, marketing analytics service providers and other third parties (collectively, "Third Party Service Providers") to, for example, facilitate personalized advertisements ("Customized Advertising") and/or other content, serve advertisements on the Site and/or measure and analyze advertising or content effectiveness and/or traffic on the Site. Customized Advertising enable us to, among other things, help deliver advertisements to you for products and services that you might be interested in based on your visits to the Site and other websites, applications or other interactive services you have visited.

Third Party Service Providers, as well as Advertisers and other third parties, may themselves set and access their own Tracking Technologies on your Device subject to your choices about those Tracking Technologies (see Sections 5.2.1 and 5.2.3 below) and/or they may otherwise collect or have access to Information about you and your online activities over time and across different websites when you use the Site.

We may also enlist the assistance of Third Party Service Providers so that the Site may set Tracking Technologies. For example, to the extent necessary to provide basic advertising serving services such as controlling how often you see advertisements or ensuring you do not see the same advertisement repeatedly, we may enlist the assistance of such Third Party Service Providers to create, customize or modify Tracking Technologies set by the Site.

Except to the extent necessary to provide services to the Site, Third Party Service Providers do not have access to Tracking Technologies set by the Site, but we may provide to Third Party Service Providers certain Information collected by Tracking Technologies set by the Site in order for the Site to provide Customized Advertising or in order for the Third Party Service Providers to provide other services to the Site, such as measuring or analyzing advertising or content effectiveness or traffic on the Site. For example, in order to analyze traffic on the Site, we may provide to our Third Party Service Providers certain information we collect about your interaction with the Site along with an Identifier so that the Third Party Service Provider may provide analytics services to the Site.

**4\. How Collected Information is Used.**

**4.1 Information You Provide.** We use the Personal Information you provide in a variety of ways, including:

* Sending marketing and promotional emails, newsletters or text messages offering goods and/or services that may be of interest to users, whether those goods and/or services are provided by the Site, Rate My Professors or third parties;
* Processing your registration with the Site, such as verifying that your email address is active and valid;
* Contacting you regarding the administration of your account, any services, features or functions you have enrolled in or registered to use, any Promotions you have participated in or have entered, any goods and/or services you have ordered through e-Commerce services available on the Site or any other transactions you have undertaken with the Site;
* Allowing you to participate in the public areas and/or other features of the Site;
* Responding to your questions or other requests;
* Contacting you regarding your use of the Site, for informational purposes related to the Site or, in our discretion, regarding changes to the Site's policies;
* Improving the Site or our services and for internal business purposes;
* Tailoring your experience on, and/or otherwise customizing what you see when you visit, the Site and/or other sites, applications or other interactive services across Devices whether owned, operated and/or provided by Rate My Professors or by third parties (for example, to provide recommendations on content or provide advertisements, emails or other content of more interest to you);
* Saving your User ID or other Personal Information, so you don't have to re-enter it each time you visit the Site;
* Otherwise to maintain and administer the Site and
* For other purposes disclosed at the time you provide the Personal Information (for example, as set forth in the Rules for any Promotions you enter).

**4.2 Identifiers and Information Collected Via Tracking Technologies.** We use the Information we collect using Tracking Technologies in a variety of ways, including:

* Keeping count of your return visits to the Site or Advertisers' or partners' sites, applications or other interactive services;
* Accumulating and reporting aggregate, statistical information in connection with the Site and user activity;
* Analyzing, determining or anticipating which features, webpages, products and services users like best to, among other things, help us operate the Site and/or other Rate My Professors websites, applications or other interactive services, enhance and improve our services and the Site and/or other Rate My Professors or third party websites, applications or other interactive services and display advertising and marketing information on the Site and/or other Rate My Professors or third party websites, applications or other interactive services (for example, to provide ads of interest to you on the Site or third party sites, to analyze effectiveness of advertisements, to assess the appeal of certain content to our general site audience and to understand your interactions with email messages we send and the content contained in such messages (such as the links clicked on within marketing and promotional emails we send and whether such messages were opened or forwarded));
* Preparing statistics reports;
* Allowing you to participate in the public areas and/or other features of the Site (for example, to enable you to use shopping carts on the Site);
* Improving our services, the Site and/or other websites, applications or other interactive services and for internal business purposes;
* Tailoring your experience on, and/or otherwise customizing what you see when you visit the Site and/or other sites, applications or other interactive services across Devices whether owned, operated and/or provided by Rate My Professors or by third parties (for example, to provide recommendations on content or provide advertisements, emails or other content of more interest to you);
* Saving certain Information for use on your return visits to the Site and making your experience on this Site more convenient for you (for example, to recognize you by name when you return to the Site, to apply certain settings or preferences you have identified on this Site or other Rate My Professors websites and to save your password in password-protected areas;
* Using certain characteristics that you enter about yourself on the Site, such as age or gender, for tailoring the online advertising and/or other content that you see when you visit the Site or other websites, applications or other interactive services whether owned, operated and/or provided by Rate My Professors or by third parties, whether alone or in combination with other Information;
* Otherwise to maintain and administer the Site (for example, to prevent you from seeing the same advertisements too many times or seeing advertisements too frequently, to record if you have opted out of receiving personalized content or using IP address to pre-populate registration fields to facilitate your sign-up);
* For the uses described for "Personal Information" above; and
* For other purposes disclosed at or before the time the Information is collected.

**4.3. Information Collected by Third Party Service Providers and Advertisers.** The use of Tracking Technologies by Third Party Service Providers and Advertisers is within their control and not ours. Even if we have a relationship with the Third Party Service Provider or Advertiser, we do not control their websites, applications or other interactive services or their policies and practices regarding your Information and you should be aware that different rules might apply to the collection, use or disclosure of your Information by third parties in connection with their advertisements or promotions and other sites, applications or other interactive services you encounter on the Internet. This Privacy Policy does not cover any use of Information that a Third Party Service Provider or Advertiser may directly collect from you. Use of Third Party Service Providers' and Advertisers' Tracking Technologies is governed by the Third Party Service Providers' or Advertisers', as applicable, own specific privacy policies and not this Privacy Policy. However, please see the "Your Choices" section for more information on how to opt-out of the collection and/or use of Information collected by certain Third Party Service Providers.

**5\. Your Choices.**

**5.1. Opting-Out of Newsletters, Marketing or Promotional Emails or Offers.** You may "opt-out" of receiving newsletters, marketing and promotional emails from the Site at any time by using the opt-out mechanism that is contained in each such email and by any other mechanisms that the Site may provide. Please note that when you opt-out of receiving these newsletters, marketing and promotional emails from us, you are not opting out of receiving marketing and promotional emails from other Rate My Professors properties. Please note that, if you deactivate your registration as a member of the Site, you shall continue to receive newsletters, marketing and promotional emails from us unless you subsequently exercise your opt-out options above. Even if you exercise your opt-out rights described above, we may continue to contact you for the other purposes described in Section 4, such as for maintenance and administrative purposes.

**5.2 Opting-Out of Tracking Technologies.** You may "opt-out" of receiving newsletters, marketing and promotional emails from the Site at any time by using the opt-out mechanism that is contained in each such email and by any other mechanisms that the Site may provide. Please note that when you opt-out of receiving these newsletters, marketing and promotional emails from us, you are not opting out of receiving marketing and promotional emails from other Rate My Professors properties. Please note that, if you deactivate your registration as a member of the Site, you shall continue to receive newsletters, marketing and promotional emails from us unless you subsequently exercise your opt-out options above. Even if you exercise your opt-out rights described above, we may continue to contact you for the other purposes described in Section 4, such as for maintenance and administrative purposes.

**5.2.1 Tracking Technologies Set By Third Parties, Service Providers and Advertisers.** Third Parties, Service Providers and Advertisers may collect information about you when you visit this Site for Customized Advertising to help identify products and services that may interest you and deliver advertising and/or other content tailored to your interests. Your opt-out options regarding these Third Party Service Providers and Advertisers are described below.

* You can opt-out of the use of tracking Information for certain advertising purposes by Google by using opt-out tools provided by Google's DoubleClick tool at [https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/#infochoices](https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/#infochoices) and provided by certain other Third Party Service Providers as described herein. If you use such opt-out tools, your choices only apply to the Third Party Service Providers identified in such links. Please note that, if third party browser cookies are disabled (whether by you or automatically by the browser or Device) or you subsequently delete browser cookies, the opt-out choices you have exercised may not function and you may need to enable third party cookies or opt out again in order for your opt-out choices to function.
* To opt out of the use of tracking Information by Third Parties, including IndexX, Magnite, Pulsepoint, Taboola, Triple Lift, PubMatic, Wunderkind, OpenX, and AdX, please visit both the Network Advertising Initiative's Opt-Out Tool and the Self-Regulatory Program for Online Behavioral Advertising opt out pages. Please note that, if third party browser cookies are disabled (whether by you or automatically by the browser or Device) or you subsequently delete browser cookies, the opt-out choices you have exercised may not function and you may need to enable third party cookies or opt out again in order for your opt-out choices to function.
* You may also prevent or exercise choices regarding the use of certain Tracking Technologies for a particular Device and Internet browser combination by using the controls for the Internet browser as described in More Information About Cookie Controls below. Please note that using those controls may affect Tracking Technologies which are browser cookies but may not affect other Tracking Technologies such as Flash LSOs.
* Nielsen Measurement: The player on this website may feature Nielsen's proprietary measurement software which will collect and use certain video viewing metrics and other information, in accordance with Nielsen's digital measurement privacy policy. For more information about Nielsen's measurement software, see [http://www.nielsen.com/digitalprivacy](http://www.nielsen.com/digitalprivacy) and see the "Choices" section of that digital measurement privacy policy to learn about your choices with respect to Nielsen's measurement, including your opt-out options if you do not wish to participate in such measurement and the scope of any opt-out options.
* In addition, the Site features Comscore's audience measurement software, which collects Information about your visit to the site. Comscore has implemented an opt-out mechanism, which allows You to opt-out of data collected by Comscore globally. The opt-out is available on [http://www.scorecardresearch.com/preferences.aspx](http://www.scorecardresearch.com/preferences.aspx). You can opt out of Comscore's sharing for Interest-Based Advertising purposes at [https://optout.aboutads.info](https://optout.aboutads.info/).
* See Section 5.2.3 below for additional information about managing Tracking Technologies set by Third Party Service Providers and Advertisers and for information on your choices regarding Identifiers on mobile platforms.

**5.2.2. Tracking Technologies Set By the Site.** With respect to the Tracking Technologies set by the Site, you have a number of options:

* You can prevent or exercise choices regarding the use of certain Tracking Technologies for a particular Device and Internet browser combination by using the controls in your Internet browser as described in Section 5.2.3 below. Please note that using those controls may affect Tracking Technologies which are browser cookies but may not affect other Tracking Technologies such as Flash LSOs.
* See Section 5.2.3 below for additional information about managing Tracking Technologies set by the Site and for information on your choices regarding Identifiers on mobile platforms.

**5.2.3. More Information on Managing Tracking Technologies.** With respect to the Tracking Technologies set by the Site, Third Party Service Providers and Advertisers, please note the following with respect to the above opt-out options:

* More Information About Cookie Controls. For the following Internet browsers, you may prevent or exercise choices regarding browser cookies for a particular Device and Internet browser combination by using the controls described in the following: Internet Explorer 11, Chrome, Safari, Firefox.

If your Internet browser is not listed above or you otherwise are having difficulties with the links, you may be able to access controls to:

* Delete existing browser cookies through the "Internet Options", "Settings", Preferences", "Options" or similar menu selection in your browser's menu or otherwise as directed by your browser's support feature, which means that all pre-existing browser cookies are deleted but does not prevent browser cookies from being used in the future.
* Disable browser cookies through the same browser controls which means that browser cookies shall not be used in the future but pre-existing browser cookies may not be deleted. Additional information on enabling or disabling browser cookies and other Tracking Technologies may be available through your browser's support feature. (See the "help" section of your browser for more information.) Disabling may sometimes be referred to as blocking or opting out of browser cookies and relies on browser cookies to remember your choices. If you delete browser cookies using the controls in your Web browser (as described above) after disabling browser cookies, you may have to disable browser cookies again to re-establish your preferences.
* Choose to have the Device you use to access the Site warn you each time a browser cookie or certain other non-Flash LSO Tracking Technology is being set. (You can later choose to turn-off such warnings.) This may be available through your Internet browser on the Device you use to access the Site. Additional information on warnings and removal of warnings may be available through your browser's support feature.
* Seek additional information from the provider of your Internet browser through your browser's support features.

The above options may cover browser cookies set by the Site, browser cookies not set by the Site (sometimes called third party cookies) and/or both types of browser cookies. **PLEASE NOTE THAT WE DO NOT CONTROL AND ARE NOT RESPONSIBLE FOR THE OPERATION OF THESE BROWSER COOKIE CONTROLS. ALSO, PLEASE NOTE THAT THESE BROWSER COOKIE CONTROLS ARE DIFFERENT FROM DO NOT TRACK OPTIONS THAT MAY ALSO BE OFFERED BY CERTAIN BROWSERS.**

* Many tools discussed above are "Internet browser cookie based." This means that such tools rely on cookies to remember your choices. For example, if you delete Tracking Technologies using the controls in your Web browser after disabling such Tracking Technologies, you may have to disable such Tracking Technologies again to re-establish your preferences and, if you exercise opt-outs through the mechanisms herein, and then delete or block browser cookies, you may need to exercise your opt-outs through these mechanisms again.
* The tools are "Internet browser and Device-specific" or "Device-specific" Note that when you exercise your options using controls for the Internet browser, your choices shall only apply to the specific Internet browser on that Device and not across Devices. This means, for example, that if you block or disable browser cookies for Internet Explorer 9 on one Device, this choice shall not block or disable browser cookies when you use Mozilla Firefox on the same Device or on a different Device using Internet Explorer 9. Further, you may need to separately exercise your options for other platforms, such as mobile platform (as described below).
* Automatic Disabling of Third Party Cookies and Effect on Certain Opt-Outs. Some Device manufacturers and/or browsers (such as Safari) may preset their browser to automatically disable browser cookies from websites, applications or other interactive services other than those you visit directly (sometimes referred to as third party cookies) and, if so, the opt-out choices you have exercised with regard to third parties may not function and you may need to enable third party cookies in order for your opt-out choices to function. For example, unless you enable third party cookies on Safari, your opt-out choices made on the Digital Advertising Alliance's Self-Regulatory Program for Online Behavioral Advertising site and on the Network Advertising Initiative site may not function.
* You shall still receive advertisements. Deleting or disabling Third Party Service Providers', Advertisers' or the Site's Tracking Technologies does not mean that you shall no longer receive online ads. If you delete or disable third party Tracking Technologies (or, if third party Tracking Technologies are automatically disabled, if you do not enable such Tracking Technologies), this only means that such ads may no longer be tailored to your specific viewing habits or interests, but you shall continue to see ads on this Site and you may see the same advertisement repeatedly or may see advertisements more frequently unless you enable Tracking Technologies set by third parties or unless we offer alternative means such as enlisting the assistance of Third Party Service Providers in order for the Site to set Tracking Technologies for frequency capping purposes as described in Section 3.2 above.
* Limitations Regarding Web Beacons. Web beacons cannot be deleted or disabled using the above opt-out options, but may be affected if such web beacons rely on browser cookies or other deleted or disabled Tracking Technologies to track your activities.
* How to Manage Flash LSOs (sometimes known as Flash Cookies). CONTROL OF FLASH LSOS (SOMETIMES KNOWN AS FLASH COOKIES) MUST BE HANDLED SEPARATELY. PLEASE NOTE THAT THE USE AND STORAGE OF FLASH LSOs TYPICALLY CANNOT BE CONTROLLED THROUGH YOUR INTERNET BROWSER. Deleting, rejecting, disabling or turning off Tracking Technologies set by Third Party Service Providers and Advertisers and set by this Site through the above options shall not remove Flash LSOs. For more information about Flash LSOs and how to remove them from your computer, please visit [http://kb2.adobe.com/cps/526/52697ee8.html](http://kb2.adobe.com/cps/526/52697ee8.html). If you remove Flash LSOs, you may not have access to certain features of the Site and some of our other services may not function properly.
* Other Effects of Managing Tracking Technologies. In addition to the above, if you delete or disable Tracking Technologies set by the Site, the Site may no longer be able to offer certain features or functionality to you, such as remembering your preferences, remembering your username, saving your player settings or other purposes described in Section 4.2 above, and some of our other services may not function properly. In addition to the above, if you disable or delete Tracking Technologies set by Third Party Service Providers and Advertisers (or if such Tracking Technologies are automatically disabled on your Device or browser), the Site may no longer be able to offer certain functionality to you, such as enabling SMN login or saving your player settings and certain services or advertisements may not work for such Devices or browsers.
* Mobile Platforms. Certain mobile platforms, such as Apple or Google, may offer users choice regarding the Identifiers we, Third Party Service Providers or Advertisers may access and use, which may not be browser cookie based. We encourage you to review and understand the choices that such mobile platforms may provide to you regarding these Identifiers.
* Certain Identifiers. Certain Identifiers we set may not be deleted, blocked or disabled using the above opt-out options, but may be affected if such Identifiers rely on, or are associated with, browser cookies or other Tracking Technologies.
* Do-Not-Track Signals and Similar Mechanisms. Some web browsers may transmit "do-not-track" signals to the websites with which the browser communicates. Because of differences in how web browsers incorporate and activate this feature, it is not always clear whether users intend for these signals to be transmitted, or whether they even are aware of them. There currently is disagreement, including among participants in the leading Internet standards-setting organization, concerning what, if anything, websites should do when they receive such signals. We currently do not take action in response to these signals, but, if and when a final standard is established and accepted, or if and when required by applicable law or regulation, we will reassess how to respond to these signals. Instead, as described above, please see the link to the Self-Regulatory Principles for Online Behavioral Advertising program that we follow that offers you choice regarding Information collected for Customized Advertising purposes and the browser cookie controls and other mechanisms described in this Section 5.2.3 and in Sections 5.2.1 and 5.2.2.

**6\. \[reserved\]**

**7\. Sharing and Disclosure of Information.**

**7.1 Sharing and Disclosure of Personal Information.** We may disclose your Personal Information to third parties under the circumstances described below.

**7.1.1 Disclosure for Marketing Purposes.** We may disclose Personal Information for marketing, administrative and/or other purposes. You can choose to opt-out of certain such uses as described in Section 5.1 above.

**7.1.2 Disclosure of Certain Information in Postings Intended to Be Disclosed.** Certain Personal Information associated with a Posting may be intended for disclosure ("Posting Information"), such as username. We shall disclose Posting Information in connection with the display of, and other services relating to, such Posting.

**7.1.3 Disclosure In Connection with Co-Branded Services and Features.** The Site may also offer services and features, such as events and Promotions, that we put together with another company ("Co-Branded Partner") and that may be hosted on the Site and/or our Co-Branded Partner's or a Promotion-specific website, application or other interactive service. The Co-Branded Partner shall be identified on the co-branded feature or service and you shall be given the opportunity to opt into any disclosure by Rate My Professors to the Co-Branded Partner for marketing purposes of Personal Information Rate My Professors collects as part of the co-branded service or feature and be provided with a link to the Co-Branded Partner's privacy policy. If you wish to opt-out of a Co-Branded Partner's future use of such Personal Information for marketing purposes, you shall need to contact the Co-Branded Partner directly and the use of such information by Co-Branded Partner is subject to Co-Branded Partner's privacy policy. Please note that your Information may be shared with Co-Branded Partners for purposes of administering or conducting the co-branded services and features (but not for marketing purposes) without a separate opt in (for example, if the Co-Branded Partner is administering a Promotion you have entered, your Information may be shared with the Co-Branded Partner so that the Co-Branded Partner can verify your eligibility and/or contact you if you are a potential winner).

**7.1.4 Disclosure to Operational Service Providers.** We also have the right to disclose your Personal Information to third parties for the purpose of administering and maintaining the Site's services, features, functions and operations. We shall refer to these third parties as "operational service providers." We use operational service providers to efficiently provide the full range of content, activities, services, features and functions we bring you and we disclose your Personal Information to operational service providers for the purpose of providing services to us.

**7.1.5 Disclosure to Certain Other Third Parties.** In addition to the above, we make your Personal Information available to certain third parties in the following limited circumstances:

* When we are compelled to do so by a governmental agency, court or other entity (e.g., to respond to subpoenas, court orders or legal process) or if requested by a governmental agency or other authority as part of an investigation;
* If we believe your actions violate any law, rule, regulation and/or the [Terms of Use Agreement](https://www.ratemyprofessors.com/terms-of-use), including, without limitation, this Privacy Policy or Additional Terms;
* In connection with Promotions, as necessary to administer the Promotion or as required by applicable laws, rules or regulations (for example, to provide winners' lists or make required filings as appropriate);
* If you agree to have your Personal Information shared with or otherwise disclosed to a third party for marketing or other purposes, in which case the third party's use of your Personal Information is subject to the third party's own privacy policy;
* If, in our sole discretion, we believe such disclosure to be necessary or appropriate: to investigate or resolve possible problems or inquiries; to protect our business and assets or the rights, property or safety of Rate My Professors, or any of its operational service providers, licensors, suppliers, Advertisers, customers, users, or any other party; to limit our legal liability; to defend our interests; to enforce this Privacy Policy or the [Terms of Use Agreement](https://www.ratemyprofessors.com/terms-of-use) and/or to comply with our legal, regulatory, audit and compliance obligations or requests by law enforcement or other governmental authorities and/or
* In the event of a bankruptcy, merger, acquisition, sale, transfer of control, joint venture or other business combination involving us.

**7.1.6 Disclosure to Affiliated Businesses.** We may share Information with affiliated businesses or other Rate My Professors properties. We do this either to provide or improve our services or to better enable those affiliates to provide their products and services to you.

**7.2 Sharing and Disclosure of De-identified Information.** We may share De-identified Information with, or otherwise disclose De-identified Information to, third parties, but we do not disclose Personal Information to them except as described in this Privacy Policy.

**8\. Reviewing, Updating or Deleting Certain Information.**

**8.1 Site Registration.** If you registered for this Site, generally, you may review, update or delete certain Information collected by the Site by, if you are a registered user of the Site, logging into the Site and using the tools provided to edit such Information. However, Personal Information that is necessary to check eligibility, such as date of birth or age, cannot be deleted, but may be modified with sufficient verification of the correct information. We shall allow you to change the password portion of your User ID, as well as certain other Information you have given us in order to keep your information current.

**8.2 \[reserved\]**

**8.3 Other Options** As a registered user, you may also be provided with options to receive certain notifications and to publicly publish activities you engage in within the Site. See also Section 10 of the [Terms of Use](https://www.ratemyprofessors.com/terms-of-use) for how registered users of this Site who are California residents and are under 18 years of age may request removal of content or Information in Postings.

**8.4 Limitations.** Certain Information collected for certain entries into Promotions are subject to corporate and regulatory recordkeeping requirements and shall not be deleted upon the user's request, unless the entrant is a child under the age of 13 years old.

If the burden or expense of providing access to your Information is disproportionate to the risks to your privacy or if the legitimate rights of others would be violated, we may decide not to provide access to such Information. In such cases, we shall provide to you an explanation of why access cannot be provided and contact information for further inquiries.

**8.5 Children or Ineligible Teenagers.** You must be at least 17 years of age to use the Site. If we inadvertently send an email or text message to a person that does not meet the age and other eligibility requirements of the Site, such as a child (a person under the age of 13) or others who do not meet the greater age requirements of the Site or certain features of this Site ("Ineligible Teenagers"), the child or Ineligible Teenager, or parent or legal guardian of the child or Ineligible Teenager (the "Parent"), may unsubscribe (opt-out) from receiving future emails or text messages via the unsubscribe mechanism contained in the email or message. The same unsubscribe process is available to a Parent of a minor (a person under the age of 18, or the age of majority in your state).

In addition, Parents who wish to terminate their child's or Ineligible Teenager's membership must either (i) use their child's or Ineligible Teenager's User ID to gain direct access to the account, and follow the procedures in the "Deactivation/Termination of Your Registration or Use" Section of the [Terms of Use Agreement](https://www.ratemyprofessors.com/terms-of-use) to terminate their child's or Ineligible Teenager's membership or (ii) contact us via the Site's Contact Us page and provide us with your child's or Ineligible Teenager's User ID, the URL of the Site and request to terminate your child's or Ineligible Teenager's account and registration or (iii), if a Parent does not have his or her child's or Ineligible Teenager's User ID, contact us via the Site's Contact Us page and include the Parent's name, address, telephone and email address, the child's or Ineligible Teenager's name and/or email address as registered on the Site, and the URL of the Site. If a Parent sends an email under subsections (ii) or (iii), the Site may send a confirming email to the Parent via the email address provided to verify that the Parent wishes to terminate his or her child's or Ineligible Teenager's account and registration and may provide or request additional information (for example, requesting that the Parent provide verifiable identification that they are the parent or legal guardian of the child or Ineligible Teenager) before terminating the child's or Ineligible Teenager's account and, upon or prior to termination, may notify the child or Ineligible Teenager of the termination request via email and identify the name, address and email address of the person making the request.

**9\. Protection of Information.** While the Internet and data transmission over the Internet is not 100% secure from intrusion, we maintain commercially reasonable physical, electronic and procedural safeguards to protect your Information. However, regardless of our efforts and the Device you use to access the Site, it is possible that third parties may unlawfully intercept or access transmissions, private communications or Information. While the Internet and data transmission over the Internet is not 100% secure from intrusion, we conduct financial transactions via secured transmissions. We also limit our employees' access to Information collected by the Site to those individuals who are authorized for the proper handling of such Information and any employee found violating our standards of security and confidentiality shall be subject to our disciplinary processes. We request that our operational service providers follow similar standards of security and confidentiality.

**Phishing.** Phishing attacks attempt to steal consumers' personal identity data and financial account credentials. "Phishers" use ‘spoofed' emails to lead consumers to counterfeit websites, or otherwise respond in a manner that is, designed to trick recipients into divulging Information such as credit card numbers, account usernames, passwords and social security numbers. WE DO NOT SEND EMAILS ASKING YOU TO PROVIDE OR CONFIRM CREDIT CARD NUMBERS, SOCIAL SECURITY NUMBERS OR YOUR USERNAME OR PASSWORD! If you receive such email communication, please forward it immediately to the Site's Privacy Administrator at [privacy@ratemyprofessors.com](mailto:privacy@ratemyprofessors.com), and then immediately delete the fraudulent email from your computer.

**10\. California Residents: Notice of Privacy Rights.** We provide this notice to comply with the California Consumer Privacy Act of 2018 as amended by the California Privacy Rights Act of 2020 (the "CCPA"). Any capitalized terms used in this notice which are not defined herein have the same meaning as defined in the CCPA.

Under the CCPA, we, as a "Business," are required to provide CA Residents with certain disclosures regarding the collection, use and disclosure of personal information, as well as certain rights to their personal information, including the right to access, delete, and correct certain personal information we collect about them. The law also restricts the "Sale" or "Sharing" of personal information for cross-context behavioral advertising, and limits the use of "Sensitive Personal Information," as defined by the law and described below. It also provides that California residents have the right not to receive discriminatory treatment for exercising the privacy rights described in this notice.

**10.1 Categories of Personal Information Collected, Purpose for Collection, and Categories of Third Parties with whom CA Personal Information is Disclosed for a Business Purpose.** The definition of personal information under California law ("CA Personal Information") is broader than the definition of Personal Information in this privacy policy and includes information we collect from you as well as Identifiers and information collected via Tracking Technologies to the extent such information is reasonably capable of being associated with or linked to a particular consumer or household. The table below lists: (i) the categories of CA Personal Information we have collected about consumers in the preceding 12 months; (ii) the categories of sources of that information; (iii) the business or commercial purposes for which the information was collected; and (iv) the categories of third parties with whom it was disclosed (including Service Providers as we define the term above).

|     |     |     |     |
| --- | --- | --- | --- |
| **Category of CA Personal Information** | **Information Collected and Categories of Sources** | **Business or Commercial Purpose for Collection** | **Categories of Third Parties With Whom CA Personal Information Was Shared** |
| **Identifiers** | Personal Information you provide us (see § 3.1)<br><br>Information collected through Tracking Technologies (see § 3.2) | Personal Information used for purposes described in § 4.1<br><br>Information collected through Tracking Technologies used for purposes described in §§ 4.1 and 4.2 | Site visitors in connection with Posting Information (see § 7.1.2)<br><br>Co-Branded Partners and Operational Service Providers (see § 7.1.3 and 7.1.4)<br><br>Government entities and other third parties (see § 7.1.5) |
| **Internet/**<br><br>**Electronic Network Activity Information** | Information collected through Tracking Technologies (see § 3.2) | Information used for purposes described in §§ 4.1 and 4.2<br><br>Third Party Service Providers and Advertisers use for Customer Advertising and related analytics and measurement as described in §§ 3.2.2 and 4.3 | Third Party Service Providers and Advertisers collect Information using Tracking Technologies (see §§ 3.2.2 and 4.3) |

In addition, we may have disclosed all of the categories of CA Personal Information identified above to the following categories of third parties: (i) judicial courts, regulators, or other government agents purporting to have jurisdiction over us, our subsidiaries or our affiliates, or opposing counsel and parties to litigation; and (ii) other third parties as may otherwise be permitted by law. We may disclose CA Personal Information to all of the third parties listed above to comply with our legal obligations or for the business or commercial purposes identified above. Additionally, we may disclose your CA Personal Information to third parties upon your request, at your direction or with your consent.

We may disclose or make available your CA Personal Information with our service providers such as our website provider, other entities that have agreed to limitations on the use of your CA Personal Information, or as otherwise permitted by, the CCPA.

**10.2 Right to Opt out of the Sale and/or Sharing of CA Personal Information.** We consider our allowing third parties to use Tracking Technologies to collect Information on the Site for Customized Advertising and other purposes described in Section 3.2.2 to be a "Sale " or "Sharing" of personal information under California law. CA Residents can opt out of the Sale and/or Sharing of their CA Personal Information by clicking on the CA Do Not Sell or Share My Personal Info link. We do not knowingly Sell or Share the CA Personal Information of any CA Residents under the age of 17.

**10.3 Use and Disclosure of Sensitive Personal Information.** Certain CA Personal Information is considered "Sensitive Personal Information" under California law, including racial or ethnic origin, religious beliefs, information regarding a mental or physical health condition or diagnosis, information regarding sex life or sexual orientation, citizenship or immigration status, union membership, genetic or biometric data, and precise geolocation data. We do not knowingly collect Sensitive Personal Information from CA Residents. To the extent that any of the information you provide or we otherwise collect about you is Sensitive Personal Information under California law, we will only use and disclose such information for the purposes specific in Section 7027(m) of the CCPA regulations.

**10.4 How to Exercise Right to Know, Correct and Deletion Requests and Non-Discrimination.** CA Residents have the right to request that we disclose the categories and/or specific information of CA Personal Information we have collected about them. CA Residents also have the right to request that we delete the CA Personal Information we collected from them, subject to certain exceptions (such maintaining the information to continue to provide our services), and to correct their CA Personal Information if it is inaccurate.

For all Site users, the categories of information we collect, the categories of sources of that information, the business or commercial purposes for which the information was collected, and the categories of third parties with whom it was shared are described above.

CA Residents may submit requests to know the specific pieces of CA Personal Information collected about them, to correct inaccurate CA Personal Information, or to have their personal information deleted by emailing us at [CCPA@ratemyprofessors.com](mailto:CCPA@ratemyprofessors.com). Requests may also be submitted via the request forms available here (for right to know specific pieces of CA Personal Information collected) and here (for deletion) and CA Residents may correct and update inaccurate CA Personal Information as described in Section 8 above. We will only be able to honor such requests for CA Residents whose identities we can verify. Registered Site users making a request via the online request form will be required to verify their identity with their User ID. Registered Site users making requests via email will be required to provide additional information relating to their account (e.g., information contained in their account profile) and/or be directed to log into their account in order to verify their identity. For non-registered Site users, the CA Personal Information collected is limited to Other Information (see Section 3). We do not have any reasonable way to verify the identity of a non-registered CA Resident making a right to know specific pieces of information or deletion request with respect to this information.

The right to request deletion of CA Personal Information does not extend to any personal information contained or displayed within a Posting on the Site, as such postings are the protected free speech of the Site user who made the Posting.

We do not discriminate or retaliate against any CA Resident for exercising any of their rights under the CCPA.

**10.5 Authorized Agents.** CA Residents may use an authorized agent to submit a request on their behalf provided that the CA Resident gives the authorized agent written permission to do so, the authorized agent submits verifiable proof of such written permission and their identity to us, and the CA Resident subsequently verifies to us that permission has been provided. CA Residents or their authorized agents can contact us at [CCPA@ratemyprofessors.com](mailto:CCPA@ratemyprofessors.com) for instructions and identity verification requirements for authorized agent requests.

**10.6 Shine the Light Law (Cal. Civ. Code § 1798.83).** A separate California law requires that we provide CA Residents with notice and choice with respect to the disclosure of their Personal Information to third parties (such as Advertisers) for marketing purposes. We provide this notice and choice in Section 7.2 above. This satisfies our obligation to otherwise maintain or furnish users with a list of the names and addresses of third parties who receive Personal Information from us for marketing purposes.

**10.7 CA Privacy Questions.** If you are a CA Resident and have additional questions regarding our collection, use or sharing of your CA Personal Information, or your CCPA or Shine the Light law rights as described in this Section, you may send us your questions by email to the Privacy Administrator at [privacy@ratemyprofessors.com](mailto:privacy@ratemyprofessors.com). All requests should be labeled "Your California Privacy Rights" on the email subject line. For all requests, please clearly state that the request is related to "Your California Privacy Rights", and include your name address and, if a registered Site user, the email address associated with your User ID.

**11\. ADDITIONAL STATE PRIVACY LAWS.** Other states, such as Connecticut, Colorado and Virginia, have also enacted privacy laws which provide their residents with various rights regarding their personal information – such as access, correction, deletion and opt out of targeted advertising – in certain circumstances. Please note that given the limited data we collect we are unable to reasonably identify the state of residence of our Site users. However, residents of all states may exercise the opt out rights described in Section 5.2 (Your Choices with Respect to Tracking Technologies).

**12\. Changes to this Privacy Policy and Notice.** We reserve the right to revise this Privacy Policy at any time for any reason in our sole discretion by posting an updated Privacy Policy without advance notice to you. Such revisions shall be effective immediately upon posting and if you use the Site after they become effective it will signify your agreement to be bound by the changes. We shall post or display notices of material changes on the Site's homepage and/or otherwise on the Site and/or e-mail you or notify you upon login about these changes; the form of such notice is at our discretion. However, we encourage you to check this Privacy Policy and [Terms of Use Agreement](https://www.ratemyprofessors.com/terms-of-use) often for updates.

**13\. Miscellaneous.**

**13.1 Accuracy and Confidentiality.** It is your responsibility to give us current, complete, truthful and accurate information, including Personal Information, and to keep such information up to date. We cannot and will not be responsible for any problems or liability that may arise if you do not give us accurate, truthful or complete information or Personal Information or you fail to update such information or Personal Information. We will reject and delete any entry that we believe in good faith to be false, fraudulent or inconsistent with this Privacy Policy.

You are solely responsible for maintaining the strict confidentiality of your User ID, if applicable, and for any charges, costs, expenses, damages, liabilities and losses we incur or may suffer as a result of your failure to do so. You, and not us, are solely responsible and liable for the activity, behavior, use and conduct on the Site under your User ID (whether used by you or any others who use your User ID), unless and until you notify us that your User ID may have been compromised, misappropriated or improperly taken or used by another party. We reserve the right to deny access, use and registration privileges to any user, including without limitation, a registered user, of any services, features or functions of the Site if we believe there is a question about the identity of the person trying to access the user's account or any services, features or functions.

Further, if you use any of the Communities features and functions made available on or through the Site, please remember that any Information disclosed in these venues is automatically made public and please use caution when disclosing any Personal Information in the Communities, as you do not know who may access and use your Personal Information or for what purposes. Rate My Professors is in no way responsible for the accuracy, use, or misuse of any information, including Personal Information, that you disclose or receive through these venues and you should assume that any disclosure you do make in these venues shall be available publicly, even without your knowledge or authorization. We reserve the right, in our sole discretion, to set certain limits on the availability of some or all features within our Communities. If you use SMN, your profile may display Information to the general public, including display name, profile URL and your member relationships, unless and if the SMN allows you to make such Information private. Publicly displayed Information and Postings may be indexed by third party search engines and appear in search results on third party websites.

**13.2 Questions.** If you have questions about this Privacy Policy, if you do not understand any information about how we collect, maintain, use or share your Personal Information or Other Information or if you would like more information about the Personal Information the Site collects about you, you may contact us directly at [privacy@ratemyprofessors.com](mailto:privacy@ratemyprofessors.com). For all requests, please include your name, street address, city, state, zip code and email address (your street address is optional if you wish to receive a response to your request via email), include the name and URL (if applicable) of the website, application or other interactive service, indicate your preference on how our response to your request should be sent (email or postal mail) and include the description "Privacy Request" in the subject of the email. We shall not accept requests via postal mail, telephone or facsimile. We are not responsible for notices that are not labeled or sent properly, or may not be able to respond if you do not provide complete information.

**13.3 Sole Statement:** This document is the sole statement of the Site's Privacy Policy and no summary, restatement or other version thereof, or other privacy statement or policy, in any form, including, but not limited to, machine-generated, is valid.

**13.4 Other:** Please review our [Terms of Use Agreement](https://www.ratemyprofessors.com/terms-of-use) which governs your use of the Site. Any terms that are not defined in this Privacy Policy shall have the meaning given in the [Terms of Use Agreement](https://www.ratemyprofessors.com/terms-of-use).

Effective: January 1, 2024

© 2024 Rate My Professors, LLC. All Rights Reserved
